Stephen Jay Gould Papers, 1899-2004
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
Stephen Jay Gould papers
1899-2004
1941-2002
M1437
Gould, Stephen Jay
564.75 Linear feet (790 boxes, 119 cartons, 30 flat boxes, 14 map folders; 160 videotapes, 271 audio cassettes, 7 reels, 35 compact discs. Computer media: 1,180 files [52 megabytes])
This collection documents the life of noted American paleontologist, evolutionary biologist, and historian of science, Stephen Jay Gould. The papers include correspondence, juvenilia, manuscripts, subject files, teaching files, photographs, audiovisual materials, and personal and biographical materials created and compiled by Gould. Both textual and born-digital materials are represented in the collection.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Rhonda Roland Shearer, 2004 (Accession 2004-148); 2005 (Accession 2005-248); 2007 (Accessions 2007-021, 2007-193, and 2007-240); 2008 (Accession 2008-099); 2009 (Accession 2009-144); 2010 (Accession 2010-018); and 2011 (Accession 2011-017).
Information about Access
Open for research, except restricted materials in Series 8. Harvard University; Series 9. New York University; Series 10. Organizations, committees, boards; Series 20. Family; and Series 23. CVs, endorsements, reviews. These restricted files are closed for research until 2086. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy. Born-digital materials are in-process and currently unavailable.
Separated Materials
Gould's rare books and manuscripts have been individually cataloged as part of the Stanford University Libraries Special Collections' rare books and manuscripts collections.
Biographical/Historical Note
Stephen Jay Gould, notable American paleontologist, evolutionary biologist, and historian of science was born on September 10, 1941, in New York City, the son of Leonard and Eleanor (Rosenberg) Gould. His father Leonard was a court stenographer, and his mother Eleanor was an artist. When Gould was five years old, his father took him to the American Museum of Natural History in New York. Gould often recalled throughout his life how viewing the Tyrannosaurus rex during this childhood trip marked the beginning of his lifelong passion for paleontology. His interest in paleontology continued to develop throughout his childhood and teenage years, and was encouraged by his family and educators. In addition to steadfast support of their boy’s academic pursuits, the Goulds were doting parents who sought to expose their child to a wide range of culture and activities, as well as a sense of civic responsibility. Though Gould’s early childhood and teenage years were largely focused on his two prevailing passions, paleontology and the New York Yankees, he also sang in school and city choirs, and was a zealous advocate for civil rights and supporter of many progressive social issues of the day.
Gould attended New York public schools, and attended Antioch College in Ohio, graduating in 1963 with a degree in Geology. During his undergraduate years he studied abroad at the University of Leeds in the United Kingdom. In 1965 he married Deborah Lee, an artist and fellow Antioch student. Together they would have two sons, Jesse and Ethan. In 1966, Gould accepted a position at Antioch College as Professor of Geology. Following his time at Antioch College, Gould attended Columbia University for his graduate work, under the guidance of mentor Norman Newell. For his doctoral thesis he investigated variation and evolution in an obscure Bermuda land snail. He earned his Ph.D. in paleontology from Columbia University in 1967. That same year he joined the faculty of Harvard University as Assistant Professor of Geology and Assistant Curator of Invertebrate Paleontology. In 1971 he was promoted to Associate Professor, and in 1973 he was promoted to Professor of Geology. In 1982 he was awarded the title of Alexander Agassiz Professor of Zoology, a position he retained until his death in 2002. From 1996 to 2002 Gould also served as Vincent Astor Visiting Research Professor of Biology at New York University. In 1972, along with Niles Eldredge, he developed the theory of punctuated equilibria. Theirs was a revision of Darwinian theory proposing that the creation of new species through evolutionary change occurs not at slow, constant rates over millions of years but rather in rapid bursts over periods as short as thousands of years, which are then followed by long periods of stability during which organisms undergo little further change.
A prolific writer, Gould authored 300 consecutive essays for his monthly column This View of Life which appeared in Natural History, the journal of The American Museum of Natural History. He also authored over 20 best-selling books, and wrote nearly a thousand scientific papers. Many of Gould's Natural History essays were reprinted in collected volumes, such as Ever Since Darwin and The Panda's Thumb. Popular treatises included books such as The Mismeasure of Man, Wonderful Life, and Full House, and his landmark work The Structure of Evolutionary Theory. Gould was also a lifelong baseball fan, and often referenced the sport in his essays. Many of his baseball essays were anthologized in his posthumously published book Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville.
In July 1982, Gould was diagnosed with peritoneal mesothelioma, a deadly form of abdominal cancer most commonly linked to asbestos exposure. After a difficult two-year recovery, Gould published a column for Discover magazine, titled "The Median Isn't the Message," which discusses his reaction to discovering that mesothelioma patients had a median lifespan of only eight months after diagnosis and the importance of statistical reasoning and the meaning of variation.
Gould was among the first group awarded the prestigious MacArthur Foundation Prize Fellowship in 1981. In 1983, Gould was awarded fellowship into the American Association for the Advancement of Science, where he later served as president (1999–2001). He also served as president of the Paleontological Society (1985–1986) and the Society for the Study of Evolution (1990–1991). In 1989 Gould was elected into the body of the National Academy of Sciences. In 2001 the American Humanist Association named him the Humanist of the Year for his lifetime of work. In his lifetime, Gould would be awarded over forty-four honorary degrees and 66 major fellowships, medals, and awards.
In 1995, Gould married artist and sculptor Rhonda Roland Shearer who is the mother of two children, Jade and London Allen, Gould’s stepchildren. Together Gould and Shearer founded the non-profit Art Science Research Laboratory, which is “committed to the creation of intellectual environment and advocacy of interdisciplinary study, encompassing the areas of research, collections and publishing.”
Stephen Jay Gould died May 20, 2002, of cancer at the age of 60.
Text for Biographical Note provided from:
http://www.stephenjaygould.org/biography.html; http://www.stephenjaygould.org/library/shermer_sjgould.pdf; http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen_Jay_Gould; http://www.biography.com/people/stephen-jay-gould-9316907
Bibliographies of Gould’s writings:
http://www.stephenjaygould.org/bibliography.html Allmon, W. D., Kelley, P. H., & Ross, R. M. (2008). Stephen Jay Gould: Reflections on his view of life. New York: Oxford University Press.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the life of noted American paleontologist, evolutionary biologist, and historian of science, Stephen Jay Gould. The papers include correspondence, juvenilia, manuscripts, subject files, teaching files, photographs, and personal and biographical materials created and compiled by Gould.
The materials found in the born-digital series were processed separately by Peter Chan, Digital Archivist for Stanford University Libraries' Department of Special Collections. For detailed processing and access information, please see notes for "Series 6: Born-Digital Materials." Audiovisual materials include audio cassettes, videotapes, compact discs, and reels. Titles were transcribed directly from media by Crystal Rengal in 2010, and the listing was incorporated into the finding aid in 2011.
Wherever Gould's original arrangement of materials was discernible, the order was retained. However, a significant portion of the materials were not well organized. Where possible, arrangement notes for the specific series will indicate which portions reflect Gould's arrangement system, and which were arranged by processing archivists.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in 23 series. The arrangement of the collection is as follows:
Series 1. Correspondence
Series 2. Juvenilia
Series 3. Manuscripts
Series 4. Subject Files
Series 5. Audiovisual Materials
Series 6. Born-Digital Materials
Series 7. Columbia University
Series 8. Harvard University
Series 9. New York University
Series 10. Organizations, committees, boards
Series 11. Conferences, lectures, and symposia
Series 12. Research
Series 13. Baseball
Series 14. Music
Series 15. Photographs
Series 16. Artifacts, ephemera, memorabilia
Series 17. Awards
Series 18. Clippings and scrapbooks
Series 19. Biographical
Series 20. Family
Series 21. Works by others
Series 22. Oversize (miscellaneous)
Series 23. CVs, endorsements, reviews (restricted)
Access Terms
American Academy of Arts and Sciences.; American Association for the Advancement of Science.; Angell, Roger; Antioch College.; Arnheim, Rudolf; Asimov, Isaac, 1920-1992; Bahamas National Trust.; Bok, Derek Curtis.; Boston Cecilia (Musical group).; Bunge, Mario, 1919-; Cain, Arthur J. (Arthur James); Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; Chomsky, Noam; Clarke, Arthur C. (Arthur Charles), 1917-2008; Clinton, Bill, 1946-; Clinton, Hillary Rodham.; Correia, Clara Pinto; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882; Dawkins, Richard, 1941-; Dershowitz, Alan M.; DiMaggio, Joe, 1914-1999; Djerassi, Carl; Ehrlich, Paul R.; Eldredge, Niles; Eysenck, H. J. (Hans Jurgen), 1916-1997; Fox, Harold Munro, 1889-1967; Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1895-1983; Gardner, Martin, 1914-2010; Gates, Bill, 1955-; Gates, Henry Louis; Gingrich, Newt; Gore, Albert, 1948-; Hallam, Anthony; Halsell, Grace; Harvard University; Huxley, Julian, 1887-1975.; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895; King, Stephen, 1947-; Krementz, Jill; Lamarck, Jean Baptiste Pierre Antoine de Monet de, 1744-1829; Leakey, Richard E.; Lewontin, Richard C., 1929-; Luria, S. E. (Salvador Edward), 1912-1991; Maynard Smith, John, 1920-2004; Mayr, Ernst, 1904-2005; Medawar, P. B. (Peter Brian), 1915-1987; Merton, Robert King, 1910-2003; Montagu, Ashley, 1905-1999; Nabokov, Vladimir Vladimirovich, 1899-1977; National Academy of Sciences.; National Science Foundation (U.S.); Newell, Norman Dennis, 1909-2005; Pauling, Linus, 1901-1994.; Raskin, Jef; Raup, David M.; Ripley, Sidney Dillon, 1913-2001; Rogovin, Milton, 1909-2011; Royal Society of Edinburgh.; Sacks, Oliver W.; Sagan, Carl, 1934-1996; Scott, Eugenie Carol, 1945-; Shearer, Rhonda Roland, 1954-; Sibley, Charles Gald, 1917-; Simpson, George Gaylord, 1902-1984; Skinner, B. F. (Burrhus Frederic), 1904-1990; Stebbins, G. Ledyard (George Ledyard), 1906-2000; Sulloway, Frank J.; Ternes, Alan; Vonnegut, Kurt; Vrba, E. S. (Elisabeth S.); Wilson, Edward O.; Wright, Sewall, 1889-1988; Baseball--Research.; Cerion; Creationism.; Evolution (Biology); Evolution.; History of Science; Natural history; Paleontology; Punctuated equilibrium (Evolution); Race discrimination.; Sociobiology.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Correspondence
  This series is comprised of Gould's incoming and outgoing letters, as well as files containing his correspondence with publishers. Included are letters, postcards, and other documents sent to Gould by colleagues, editors, publishers, and fans. Letters from colleagues include discussion of collaborative projects, activities relating to professional organizations, routine correspondence regarding conferences and travel arrangements, and requests for recommendations, manuscript reviews, and article reprints. Letters from fans and laypersons include both praise and criticism of Gould's books, scholarly articles, popular science works, and involvement in the fields of evolutionary biology, paleontology, and the history of science. Also included are personal letters from colleagues, family, and friends. Gould routinely kept copies of outgoing letters for some time. Primarily these consist of letters to professional colleagues, though there are some responses to fan mail, typically replies to children who wrote letters to Gould about their interest in science and to fans who wrote to Gould in regards to their battles with cancer.
  About incoming letters:
  Incoming letters were received primarily between 1963 and Gould's death in 2002. Also included are condolence letters that were sent to Gould's mother and widow after his death.
  The first twelve subseries of incoming letters remain as originally ordered in Gould's chronological files and are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. In cases where a substantial number of letters exist for a correspondent, or where the author or subject matter is of particular significance, the letters are foldered individually by correspondent. Letters foldered separately appear at the beginning of each alpha range and are followed by general alpha arrangement (for example, "Abrams, Susan" then "Aa-Ae"). Some date range overlap exists between subseries as original order was maintained.
  The "Incoming letters arranged by date" subseries includes letters found throughout Gould's papers, which have been arranged by year of receipt. The "Incoming letters arranged by subject" subseries includes letters that were clearly grouped together by subject throughout Gould's papers. These files have been labeled in keeping with Gould's own organizational scheme, and consist of invitations and appearance requests, condolence letters received after Gould's death, and letters to Gould found laid in his rare books.
  "Incoming letters from prominent figures" is a discrete collection of letters from scientists and public figures that Gould maintained separately from his other letters. Letters have been arranged by date, and a detailed list of correspondents is provided for each folder.
  About outgoing letters:
  Outgoing letters date from approximately 1963 until Gould's death in 2002 and are grouped in two subseries. Both are ordered chronologically, the first subseries is ordered by month sent with letters of particular note indicated in the folder title; the second subseries is ordered by year and includes replies authored by Gould's research assistants. Letters include routine correspondence with editors, discussion of professional matters, responses to fan mail, and personal messages.
  About correspondence with publishers:
  This subseries includes letters to and from publishers and is arranged by date. Most often these letters are grouped together, in reference to a particular book project.
  Notable correspondents include Susan E. Abrams, Isaac Asimov, Edwin Barber, Jimmy Carter, Arthur C. Clarke, Bill Clinton, Hillary Clinton, Richard Dawkins, Alan Dershowitz, Joe DiMaggio, Carl Djerassi, Niles Eldredge, R. Buckminster Fuller, Martin Gardner, Bill Gates, Henry Louis Gates, Jr., Mikhail Gorbachev, Al Gore, Anthony Hallam, Grace Halsell, Edward M. Kennedy, Ernst Mayr, Sir Peter Medawar, Robert K. Merton, Ashley Montagu, Norman D. Newell, Linus Pauling, Jef Raskin, David M. Raup, Milton Rogovin, Carl Sagan, Eugenie Scott, Charles Sibley, George Gaylord Simpson, B. F. Skinner, John Maynard Smith, G. Ledyard Stebbins, Alan Ternes, Kurt Vonnegut, E. O. Wilson, and Sewall Wright.
  - Subseries 1. Incoming letters, 1975-1979
    - Addicott, Warren O. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ager, D. V. (Derek Victor) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Aldrich, Michele L. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Allen, Garland E. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Appleman, Philip (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Aronson, Lester R. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Atchley, William R. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Awramik, S. M. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Abelson, Philip H.; Abler, William L.; Abrahamsen, Valerie; Affleck, Marilyn; Ahrnsbrak, William F.; Akersten, William A.; Alberch, Pere; Albritton, Claude; Aldridge, R. J.; Alexander, Richard R.; Allen, Arly; Allen, Gary L.; Allen, Richard M. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Alley, Thomas R.; Alt, David; Anderson, Paul K.; Anderson, R. S.; Apsey, Robert Patrick; Armbruster, Bruce; Arnheim, Rudolf; Arnstein, Walter L.; Arthurs, Alberta; Ausich, William I.; Steven A. Austin; Ayala, Francisco J. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Baer, A. J. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Baity, Elizabeth Chesley (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Baker, Victor R. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bambach, Richard K. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Banks, Edwin M. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Barber, Edwin (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bardach, Barbara (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Barlow, George W. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Barry, David G. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bates, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Batten, Roger L. and Niles Eldredge (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bauchot, Roland (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Mullen, B. Gail (Beagle) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Behnke, James W. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Behnke, John A. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Behrensmeyer, Kay (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bell, Daniel (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bell, Michael A. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Belliveau, Marion C. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bennett, Thomas Peter (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Bennett, William (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Bennett-Mendez, Kate (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Berg, Sheila (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Berger, Edward (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Berger, Jacques (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Berggren, William A. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Berkstresser, Charles F., Jr. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Bethell, Tom (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Bishop, Martin (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Blake, Robert (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Blouw, Max (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Bolt, John R. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Bookstein, Fred L. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Borras, Catherine (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Bowler, Peter (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Bretsky, Peter W. (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Bretsky, Sara S. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Bretting, Peter (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Brewster, Beatrice (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Brower, James C. (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Brown, Thomas M. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Brown, William L., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Brownstein, Larry (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Brunauer, Patricia A. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bunge, Mario (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bunn, James (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Burkhardt, Frederick (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Burnett, Farrell (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Burns, John M. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Burstyn, Harold L. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bagnara, Joseph T.; Bahm, Archie J.; Baker, James J.; Ball, John; Ballester, George, Jr.; Balon, Eugene K.; Baranowitz, Steven; Bardack, David; Barker, Crystal L.; Basden, Andrew; Baur, Werner H.; Bayley, S. T.; Bayliss, Catherine; Baynes, Alex; Kerr, Jane (Beale); Beaman, John H.; Beatty, John; Becker, Barbara A.; Beerbower, James R.; Beers, William H.; Bekoff, Marc; Bell, A. T. J.; Bell, Ian F. A.; Belt, Edward S. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Benford, Frank A.; Bennett, Ralph A.; Bergman, Barrie F.; Bernardi, Nelson; Bernhardt, Kim; Berry, Joyce; Berry, R. J.; Bertoni, Elisabetta; Beyer, Brian Nolan; Biedenweg, Doug; Bigwood, B. A.; Bijur. Victoria; Billings, Marland P.; Bingler, Edward C.; Birks, H. J. B.; Bjurstedt, Hilding; Black, Craig C.; Black, Simon; Blankenship, Jacob W.; Blanpied, William A.; Den Boer, James (Filed under "Boer"); Bogoch, Samuel; Bok, Derek C. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bonem, Rena M.; Bonner, J. T.; Boot, K. J.; Boss, Kenneth J.; Boucot, Arthur J.; Bowersock, G. W.; Boyce, A. J.; Boyd, F. R.; Boyer, Robert E.; Boylan, P. J.; Brace, C. Loring; Bradbury, Jack W.; Brady, Peter; Brannigan, Gus; Bravo, Ernesto; Bray, John; Briggs, Doras; Briskin, Madeleine; Brolin, Brent; Brothwell, D. R.; Brown, Edward H.; Brown, Phyllis G.; Brownlow, Arthur; Brussard, P. F.; Bryce, George W., Jr.; Buck, Peter; Bull, William B.; Burch, J. B.; Burchsted, Frederic F.; Burian, Richard M.; Burke, Richard; Burlingame, Leslie J.; Burnett, Christopher; Byrne, H. Desmond; Bywaters, Tom (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - B Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Cain, A. J. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Campbell, Norm A. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Campbell, Robert (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Caplan, Arthur (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Carey, William D. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Carson, Hampton (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Carson, Teresa (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Caster, Kenneth (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Chappell, John E., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Ciochan, Russell L. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Clark, George R., II (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Clench, William J. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Cloud, Preston (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Cobb, W. Montague (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Cohen, Irene (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Cohen, Robert S. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Cole, Mike (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Coleman, William (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Collicott, Andrew Bottan (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Coon, Carleton (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Conrad, Ernie (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Cook, James (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Crompton, A. W. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Cronin, Tom (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Crumly, Charles R. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Currie, Philip J. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Cairns, James A; Camber, Bruce Earl; Cameron, Barry; Campbell, Donald T; Campon, Rita; Cantor, Gordon; de Caprariis, Pascal; Carawan, Talmage; Carey; Thomas; Carlisle; E. Fred; Carr, W. J.; Carroll, Robert L.; Carroll, Thomas P; Carter; Joseph; Cartmill, Matt Caswell, Hal (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Cerva, Barbara; Chaisson, Eric; Chalmiers; Harry; Char, M. B. S.; Chartkoff, Joesph L.; Chase, Allan; Chastain, R. Murray; Chatterjee, Sankar; Cherfas, Jeremy; Chevalier, Peggyann; Childers, David W.; Christenson, Terry E.; Chu, Penn Richard; Churchill, Frederick (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Clark, George M.; Clark, Sarah F.; Clayton, Robert N.; Clegg, Michael T.; Clemens, W. A.; Cock, Alan; Coe, Robert; Cogan, Robert D.; Cohen, Alvin; Cohen, Hyman; Cohen, Jack; Cohen, Nathan; Cohen, Ralph; Colbert, Edwin H.; Cole, Charles J.; Cole, John R.; Cole, Ned S.; Coleman, Jules; Collins, D. H.; Collins, James P.; Colp, Ralph, Jr.; Colwell, Robert K. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Condon, Margaret (Peg); Congdon, Gordon; Connor, Edward F.; Conroy, Glenn; Cooper, Brenda; Cooper, Edwin L.; Corey, Gail Sprecht; Corliss, John O.; Corr, Michael; Corrsin, Stanley; Cota-Robles, Eugene H.; Coull, Bruce C.; Cowen, Richard; Cox, Stephen F.; Cracraft, Joel; Craig, G. Y.; Crawford, Daniel J.; Crow, James F.; Crowell, Kenneth; Cruise, James E.; Cymes, Sue (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - C Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Danielli, James (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Darling, D. Chris (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Davis, Charles C. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Davis, George M. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Dawkins, Richard (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Debus, Allen C. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Decker, Robert W. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - DeHaan, Robert L. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Delson, Eric (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - DeMott, Lawrence (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Desmond, Adrian (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Devons, Samuel (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Dickinson, Mary H. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Dillon, Robert (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Doyle, James A. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Dunne, Jack (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Dunson, William A. (Box 3, Folder 21)